Andrés Isaac Biso

City of Buenos Aires, Argentina



in linkedin.com/in/andresbiso



https://andresbiso.netlify.app/en/

Summary

Let's connect:

☑# Twitter (@andres_biso)

☑# Contact: https://andresbiso.netlify.app/#contact ☑# LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andresbiso/

If your company or organization would like to add new points of view on how to solve problems, let me be part of that change. Here is the story on how I decided to choose this career.

Since I was a kid I have always been interested in computers. My passion for programming started when I found a program that let me create my own video games. That experience ignited the spark that made me decide to choose the orientation in Computing and Digital Media during high school. After that I enrolled on the Information Systems Engineering career later on and that led me on becoming a software developer.

During my time as a developer, I have worked on a wide range of projects for different companies. I find working as a developer fun and challenging. From working on these projects, I demonstrated strong abilities programming in Angular and .NET. I was also able to improve my communication skills in english being nowadays able of explaining technical issues to non-technical audiences with that language.

Experience



Senior - Full-Stack Software Developer

Hexacta

Dec 2019 - Present (9 months +)

- Eaton Vance: Development of the internal Sherpa tool. Its role is to consolidate business data from multiple sources in one location, aiming to provide one consolidated place for all their daily information needs. Sherpa meets these daily business data needs with a single, convenient source that allows users to compare, analyze, and view all the data needed through the same application.

Semi-Senior - Full-Stack Software Developer

Hexacta

Feb 2017 - Dec 2019 (2 years 11 months)

- Philip Morris: Development of promotional sites of different brands, such as Marlboro Fresh, Gold Marlboro, Virginia Slims, Philip Morris. The aim of the "work cell" was the development and support for the various stages of the sites, managing the team's time to meet the requirements of Marketing, One to One, Massalin (Philip Morris International's associate in Argentina).
- Americaneagle.com: The project involved the development of multiple websites to AmericanEagle.com based both idev® CMS (owner of AE) and on Sitefinity (Telerik) and Umbraco. Several of these sites are still in progress.
- Universidad Argentina de la Empresa: The project consisted of the implementation and configuration of a CMS that enabled the UADE marketing area to keep the institutional site updated in a simple and flexible way.

Internship - Software Developer

Hexacta

Aug 2015 - Jan 2017 (1 year 6 months)

- Audigraphics: Development of AudiGraphics website. It was a system of B2B information services delivered by two client websites - one for radio stations (Station AudiGraphics) the other for broadcast networks and program producers, distributors, and funders (National AudiGraphics). It provided reports and statistics on radio audience.
- Philip Morris: Development of promotional sites of different brands, such as Marlboro Fresh, Gold Marlboro, Virginia Slims, Philip Morris. The aim of the "work cell" was the development and support for the various stages of the sites, managing the team's time to meet the requirements of Marketing, One to One, Massalin (Philip Morris International's associate in Argentina).

√ Técnico

Randstad

Jun 2015 - Jul 2015 (2 months)

Technician in charge of the e-voting machines during the elections in CABA.

CIDER® Technician

CIDeR

Apr 2015 - Apr 2015 (1 month)

Technician in charge of the e-voting machines during the PASO elections in CABA.

Education

* Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

Information Systems Engineering, Information Technology 2012 - Present

ORT Argentina

Technical High School Diploma with orientation in Computing and Digital Media 2007 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications



First Certificate in English (FCE) - University of Cambridge

Skills

Angular • .NET • English • Scrum • Kanban • Agile & Waterfall Methodologies • JavaScript • AngularJS • Git · Microsoft SQL Server